

DIOGO BRATTI <u>dbratti@gmail.com</u> / +55 48 99951-8667 <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/diogo-bratti/</u> <u>https://github.com/diogobratti</u>

FULL STACK AND MOBILE ENGINEER

Proactive, responsible JavaScript, Dart and PHP developer focused on mobile and full stack position. Have great soft skills, being an easy person. Known to show strong technical knowledge and to deliver solid systems. More than 7 years experience developing successful systems and 6 years managing IT projects. Active at open source project at GitHub.

SELECTED HIGHLIGHTS

- Successfully managed a major upgrade version at a 10,000 clients software.
- Successfully managed a 17 developers team.
- Cocreated two open source mobile apps, one using React Native and firebase and the other using Flutter and WebRTC.

KEY COMPETENCIES			
Software engineering	Team management experience	Agile methodologies	
Programming	Technical Expertise	Mobile development	
Full stack development	Open source	Communication skills	

EDUCATION

Universidade do Sul de Santa Catarina (UNISUL), Florianopolis (SC), Brazil IT Projects Management Specialist

Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina (UFSC), Florianopolis (SC), Brazil Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TJSC / Florianopolis (SC), Brazil / September 2011 – present System Analyst (part-time)

TJSC (Tribunal de Justiça de Santa Catarina) is a Brazilian State Court. www.tjsc.jus.br

- Utilize extensive software development skills to develop systems in PHP (eproc).
- Supervised a software maintaining contract.
- Successfully leaded a developers team. The team started with 5 developers and ended with 17 developers. The software has 10 thousand users, and it was developed in PHP/MySQL (eproc). This software was installed in a year and half.
- Worked as a project manager in a major version software (SAJ) upgrade. The

software have 10 thousand users and controls process of a State Court in Brazil. The software's previous version manage only paper law process. After that, almost all law processes are digital. Later this software was replaced by eproc.

Softplan / Florianopolis (SC), Brazil / February 2010 – September 2011 IT Support

Softplan is a technology developer and supplier. <u>www.softplan.com.br</u>

- Successfully extracted Oracle / DB2 / SQL Server database reports.
- Worked as level 1 support.

Floripa Software / Florianopolis (SC), Brazil / 2009 Software Developer Intern

PERSONAL PROJECT

Open software mobile app to help elder people find someone to take care of them June 2019 – present

With help of 2 partners, I have built a react native app called "iCare" to help elder people find someone to take care of them. It was developed using react native and Google Firebase backend and authentication. https://github.com/diogobratti/iCare-app

Open software mobile app to audio chat without Internet August 2023 – present

I have created a flutter app called "motorcom" to make people audio chat without Internet (example Wi-Fi Direct, Bluetooth), being used mainly when two people are riding a motorcycle in countryside and want to communicate to each other through headsets. It was developed using Flutter and WebRTC. https://github.com/diogobratti/motorcom

LANGUAGES		
Portuguese - Native	English - Advanced	
Spanish – Intermediate	Italian – Intermediate	

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

3 years of Italian Lessons; Centro de Cultura Italiana: 2006

ADDITIONAL CREDENTIALS		
TECHNICAL SKILLS	Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) / Oracle / MySQL / Scrum / Visual Studio Code / Git / PHP / React Native / JavaScript / Firebase / Flutter / UML	
OTHER ACTIVITIES AND PROJECTS	Work experience program in the USA.Open source mobile app at GitHub	
HOBBIES AND INTERESTS	Biking	